本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
目の前に立ちはだかる高い高い壁
A massive, massive wall stands
in front of me, blocking my way.
Aoba Jousai                  Karasuno
I wonder what the view is like on the other side.
その向こうはどんな眺めだろうか
What does it look like?
どんなふうに見えるのだろうか
The view from the summit—
頂の景色
俺独りでは決して見ることのできない景色
it's something I'll never be able to see alone.
But...
独りではないのなら
if I'm not alone...
I just might be able to see it.
見えるかもしれない景色
Episode One:
Let's Go To Tokyo!
Red                White
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
来た
Here it comes.
All right! Here I go!
よしゃ行くぜ
Yeah!
Whoo!
Wh-Whoo...
Get used to it already.
いい加減慣れろ
Give us a good one, Daichi!
大地さんナイサ
オライ
Got it!
Left!
レフト
旭が好きな少し高めのトス
Asahi likes his sets slightly high.
チャンスボル
We can score here!
Got it!
オライ
It's coming again.
もう一回来るぞ
ホント面白いように引かかてくれるね
It's funny how you keep falling for that.
What'd you say?!
Now, now...
ナイサ
Give us a good serve!
うまくいかない
It just never seems to work.
Who'll it be this time?
今度はどちだ
Gah!
ロリングサンダ
Was that Rolling Thunder?!
Yeah!
Rolling... Thunder!
ロリングサンダ
Sorry! I was completely open too!
すまねぇ完全フリだた
So annoying...
うるさい
All right, let's switch gears!
よし切り替えていくぞ
Yessir!
Give us a good serve, Yamaguchi!
山口ナイサ
日向
Hinata!
We're gonna stop it!
とめる
ナイスカバ
Nice cover!
Red                White
All right!
よしゃ
Okay, that's enough for today.
よし今日はここまでだ
Let us play one more set, please!
もう１セトお願いします
Huh?
Please!
お願いします
Guys, playing until you drop isn't the answer.
あのな我武者羅にやりゃいいてモンじゃねぇぞ
Captain, you need to tell these guys—
キャプテンお前からも何とか言てや
お前らな
You guys...
Miyagi Prefectural
Karasuno High School
Red                White
I still need to practice hitting.
まだ打ち足りないまだ
Kageyama! You can still go, right?
影山まだいけるよな
Set for me!
トス上げてくれ
Sure.
You guys are still gonna practice?
まだやんのかよお前ら
Hey! We've still got to clean up, so that's enough for today!
They're all definitely realizing their own potential, but what our team lacks is experience.
こら片付けもあるんだぞ今日はもう終わり
地力は確実についてきてる
しかしうちのチムに足りないのは経験
Yes, sir...
Hey, make sure you cool down properly.
おいちゃんとダウンしろよ
They definitely haven't had enough
practice matches against other teams.
外のチムとの練習試合が全然足りねぇ
Ow!
痛い
I can't count on the neighborhood association always being available. What should I do?
町内会は安定して人集まらねぇしどうする
Sir?
先生
Take?
武ちゃん
You okay?
大丈夫か
W-We're going, right?
い行きますよね
Where?
どこに
Your nose is bleeding!
鼻血出てます
Tokyo!
東京
Tokyo?
東京てもしかして
You mean...
Volleyball Team (Boys)
Nekoma?!
音駒ですか
Gross!
汚ねぇ
Here! A tissue!
ティシュ
A practice match?
練習試合スか
Yeah!
But we won't be playing just Nekoma this time.
駒だけじゃないんだ
The Fukurodani Academy Group.
梟谷学園グルプ
It's a group of schools from the
Kanto region that includes Nekoma.
音駒を含む関東の数校でできているグルプで
Apparently, they hold practice matches regularly.
普段から練習試合などを盛んに行ているそうなのですが
Thanks to Coach Nekomata,
we'll be able to take part this time.
今回猫又監督の計らいで
その合同練習試合に烏野も参加させてもらえることになりました
Groups like that are created through relationships built up over years,
そういうグルプは昔から積み上げた関係性みたいなモンでできてるから
so it's not easy to get in without connections.
ツテ無しではなかなか入れるモンじゃないんだが
We'll have to make sure to thank Coach Nekomata.
猫又監督に感謝だな
And Mr. Takeda here, who I'm sure kept persistently asking him.
あとまたしつこく頼んでくれたであろう先生にもな
No, I didn't really...
いや僕はそんな
Coach Ukai's name helped a lot.
烏養監督のお名前あてこそで
Thank you!
あざす
Over the years, we've lost connections with other schools in the prefecture that we used to be friendly with.
この数年で県内で昔懇意にしていた学校とも疎遠になてしまた
There are many schools where the coaches that were once close to Coach Ukai are now gone.
当時の烏養監督と親しかた指導者が変わてしまた学校も少なくないです
We shouldn't pass up this opportunity.
このチャンス活かさない手はないです
Yeah!
I'm going to be able to see that setup up-close again.
あのセトアプまた間近で見れんのか
Maybe I caught a cold.
風邪ひいたかな悪寒が
I'm getting chills.
Hey! We have a tournament soon!
うおおい大会前だぞ
This time, I'm going to protect us 'til we win!
今度は俺が護り勝ァァつ
Yeah... It might actually be a little cold today.
確かに今日ちょと寒い
夜久さんも
You too, Yaku?!
We're gonna take down that City Boy Alliance!
シティボイ連合に殴り込みじゃあぁ
シティボイ
City Boy...
連合
...Alliance?
I'm feeling hot! I'm burning up!
俺はなんか暑い熱いですよぉぉ
山本うるせぇ
Yamamoto, shut it.
I'm gonna break through their blocks this time for sure!
今度は絶対ブチ抜いてやる
Um, the only thing is, their prelims for the interhigh start this weekend, so it won't be right away.
ええとただ向こうはインタハイ予選が今週末からなので
すぐてわけではないです
Also, at this point, we've only received the invitation.
あとまだ「お誘い」をいただいている段階でして
There are some things we have to work out, but I'll give you the details another time.
色々承諾をもらわないといけないことなど
細かいことはまた後でお話ししますね
Anyway, it seems like you all...
とりあえず皆の意思は
Of course!
勿論
行きます
We'll go!
I've got a staff meeting, so I've got to get going.
じゃあ僕これから職員会議なので行きますね
Ukai, I'll leave the rest to you.
烏養君あとよろしくお願いします
Sure.
Thank you, sir!
あざす
忙しくなるな
It's going to get busy.
Yeah.
You'll be busy too, Shimizu.
清水もな初遠征だもんな
It'll be your first series of away games with us.
I'll do my best too.
私も頑張る
C'mon! Hurry and clean up, and then go home!
ほらささと片付けて帰るよ
Yessir!
うす/おす
The food was great!
ごちそうさまでした
I wonder who it is.
誰だろ
Is she a third-year?
三年生かな
So pretty...
美人
What's up? Something happening?
なになにどうしたの
Shimizu!
清水先輩
Hinata knows the hot third-year?!
日向が三年生の美女と知り合い
Wh-What are you do... do...
こんなとこでどどう
Hey, Hinata?
日向あのね
Do you know any first-years who haven't joined a club?
一年生でどの部活にも入てない子てわかる
Aoba Jousai High School
Oikawa Tooru (Third-Year)
Oikawa's featured in Monthly Volleyball,
and it even has his picture.
月バリに及川がそれも写真付きで
Well, he is one of the best in the country.
まあ実力は全国クラスだからな
So, what does it say?
んでなんて書いてあんだ
Let's see here...
ええと
"Oikawa's favorite food is milk bread.
及川選手の好きな食べ物は牛乳パン
His favorite saying is, 'If you're going to hit it, hit it until it breaks.'"
座右の銘は「叩くなら折れるまで」
なんだそりゃあ
What the hell is that?
Why would anyone care about such pointless information?!
そんな余計な情報はいらねぇよ
Third-Years Remain to
Take Down Shiratorizawa
Looks like Seijou wants to take down Shiratorizawa,
青城は「打倒白鳥沢」を目指して
so most of the third-years who were starters are staying on the team!
レギュラだた三年生がほとんど残たらしいスね
Come on and bring it, Seijou!
おら青城かかてこいやぁぁ
Bring it!
こいやぁぁ
おい破れるだろ
Hey! You're gonna rip it!
For crying out loud.
The Reigning Champions of Tohoku
Shiratorizawa Academy
Ushijima Wakatoshi
(Third-Year)
Wing Spiker
Hey, it's Ushiwaka.
ウシワカだ
The Reigning Champions of Tohoku
Shiratorizawa Academy
Ushijima Wakatoshi
(Third-Year)
Wing Spiker
Shiratorizawa Academy
Ushijima Wakatoshi
(Third-Year)
Wing Spiker
Shiratorizawa Academy
(Third-Year)
Wing Spiker
"Japan"?
ジャパン
Hey! Get out here already.
おいささと外を出ろランニングに行くぞ
We're going for a run.
Hey... Ushiwaka's on the youth world team.
いやウシワカが世界ユスに入てる
What?
Youth world team?
世界ユス
Simply put, he's representing Japan in the under 19 age group.
簡単に言うと１９歳以下の日本代表
Only one high school can represent Miyagi at spring nationals.
春高で宮城の代表になれるのは１校だけ
For us to go to there,
俺たちが全国に行くには
ウシワカや及川を倒さないといけないわけだ
we'll have to defeat Ushiwaka and Oikawa.
よしゃランニング行くぞ
All right! Let's go running!
Yessir!
Faculty Office
Quiz
Name\Class:
Tanaka Ryuunosuke
Class 2-1
Quiz
Name\Class:
Nishinoya Yuu
Class 2-3
This is reality.
これは現実だ
I need to accept it and think rationally.
まず受け止めて冷静に
It'll be okay.
大丈夫ガツあるあの子たちならできる
Those kids have plenty of guts, so they can do this.
They can do it if they try.
やればできるやれば
They can do it if—
They can do it if they try. They can do it if they try.
やればできるやればできるやればできる
Mr. Takeda?!
武田先生
Here we are.
来たぜ烏野名物ハトブレイクヒル
Karasuno's famous Heartbreak Hill.
All right! Ten dashes uphill to the halfway mark!
よし中腹まで坂道ダシュ十本
Two at a time!
二人ずつな
On your marks...
用意
月島全力で走れ
Tsukishima! Run like you mean it!
On your marks...
用意
Hey. Good job, Tsukishima.
月島お疲れ
Hey! Where are you guys going?!
おいどこまで行くんだお前ら
Pretty sure we can just let them go.
もういいんじゃないですかほとけば
Morons. Morons. Morons.
No one's behind us.
誰もついて来ない
You totally went the wrong way somewhere, didn't you?
お前途中で道間違えただろう
That'd be you, dumbass!
お前だろうボケ
Where are we?
どこだろうここ
Wakano 3-chome?
若野３丁目
Isn't Wakano near Shiratorizawa?
若野て言えば白鳥沢の近くじゃないか
Shiratorizawa? Like the school Ushiwaka goes to?
白鳥沢てウシワカの
Did you need something from me?
俺に何か用か
Japan!
ジャパン
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
Japan!
ジャパン
If you don't need anything, I'll be leaving.
用がないなら行く
We came from Karasuno!
俺達烏野から来ました
Would you mind if we did some recon at Shiratorizawa?
白鳥沢の偵察させてもらえませんか
Is he serious?!
こいつマジか
偵察てこそりやるもんじゃねぇの
Aren't you supposed to recon in secret?
Karasuno...
烏野おかしな速攻を使うチムだな
The team that uses that weird fast attack?
Do as you like.
好きにしろ
No matter how skilled you may be,
お前達の実力がどうあても
we won't get weaker just because you watched us.
見られることで俺達が弱くなることはない
I'm heading back to school now.
これから学校に戻る見たいならついて来ればいい
If you want to watch, follow me.
If you can keep up.
ついて来られるんなら
We're going.
行くだろ春高で倒す相手だ見て損はねぇ
We're gonna defeat you at spring nationals.
Of course we'll watch.
Yeah.
Are you out jogging by yourself?
一人でロドワク中ですか
Everyone else is just slow.
他の連中が遅いだけだ
They're back there somewhere.
後ろのどこかにいる
Kageyama!
影山フライングすんなよ
Don't you dare get a head start!
You're just slow!
てめぇが遅ぇんだよ
Unsurprisingly, he keeps a quick pace.
さすがのハイペスだな
Holy crap! I'm super excited!
やべぇなんかテンション上がる
Whoo!
Calm down, dumbass! Are you a dog?
落ち着けボケが
犬か初めての散歩かアホが
Are you out for your first walk, you idiot?!
Shiratorizawa Academy
It's so big!
ひろぉぉ
校舎かけぇなんかホテルとかみてぇ
Their school building looks so cool!
It looks like a hotel!
What's with this super-huge sports ground?!
なんだこのめちゃ広い運動場は
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Whoa! This place is so big they need signs!
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
広すぎて看板あるぞ
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Management Center/Parking Lot
Indoor Practice Area/Baseball Field
Golf Practice Area/Tennis Courts
Kageyama! Horses!
影山馬馬いる
They have horses!
The volleyball team has its own bus!
バレ部専用バス
おい迷子になるなよ
Hey. Don't get lost.
I won't!
ならねぇよ
牛島さん見失たぞ
We've lost sight of Ushijima!
じゃ迷子だよ
Then we're lost!
This looks like it might be the volleyball team's gym.
ここぽいなバレ部の体育館
Yeah.
Hey, can you see Ushiwaka?
見えるウシワカ見えるか
Shut up! And stop pushing me!
うせぇ押すな
Huh?
あれ他の学校がいねぇか
Isn't that another school?
Is it a practice match? Who're they playing?
練習試合相手は
あれ大学生じゃねぇか
Aren't those college students?
College?!
大学
Well, no other high school in the prefecture stands a chance against Shiratorizawa.
県内には白鳥沢の相手になる高校はもういねぇからな
They'd have to go outside the prefecture or have a
college team come in for it to even count as practice.
県外に行くか大学生くらいしか練習にならねぇんだろうな
Curse you, Japan!
ジャパンめ
Took you long enough.
遅かたな
I'm Kageyama from Karasuno High School.
俺は烏野高校の影山です
Would you mind if I had a look?
偵察してもいいですか
Kageyama...
影山北川第一か
From Kitagawa First, right?
はいここを受けて落ちました
Yes.
I applied to this school, but wasn't accepted.
That's not surprising.
だろうな
I remember seeing one of your matches from junior high.
中学のお前の試合を見た覚えがある
We have no need for setters who can't devote themselves to their aces.
エスに尽くせないセタはうちにはいらない
It's true. You're not the type that'd be devoting!
確かにお前尽くすて感じじゃねぇな
What?!
But the same would go for the Great King too, wouldn't it?
でもそれだと大王様もだよな
And he's the best setter in the prefecture.
県内最強セタなのにな
Oikawa has nothing to do with this!
及川さんは今関係ねぇだろ
及川やつは優秀な選手だうちへ来るべきだた
Oikawa...
He is an efficient player.
He should have come to our school.
By that, do you mean Oikawa would be able to devote himself to you?
及川さんならあなたに尽くすてことですか
及川はどこであろうとそのチムの最大値を引き出すセタだ
No matter where he is, Oikawa is a setter that can bring out the absolute best in his team.
If the team's absolute best is still weak, there's nothing more to be done.
チムの最大値が低ければそれまで
If it's strong, he'll make it as strong as possible.
高ければ高いだけ引き出す
That is where his abilities lie.
それがやつの能力だ
A sapling must have good soil in order to grow strong.
優秀な苗にはそれに見合た土壌があるべきだ
痩せた土地で立派な実は実らない
Good fruit cannot be harvested from barren soil.
痩せた土地
Barren soil?
どういう意味ですか
What do you mean?
Other than Oikawa, everyone at Aoba Jousai is weak.
青葉城西は及川以外弱いという意味だ
Weak...
弱い
If Seijou is barren soil,
青城が痩せた土地なら俺達はコンクリトか何かですかね
does that make us concrete or something?
He usually gets intimidated by strong-looking opponents when he first meets them, yet...
こいついつも初対面の強そうな相手にはビビるくせに
I apologize if I hit a nerve,
何か気に障たのなら謝るが
but someone on a team that can't even make it to the prefecture finals because they lost to Aoba Jousai
青葉城西に負け県内の決勝にも残れないものが
can say all they want, but I will make nothing of it.
何を言てもどうとも思えん
He...
こいつ
I'm Hinata Shouyou, from the concrete.
コンクリト出身日向翔陽です
I'm gonna crush you
あなたをぶ倒して全国へ行きます
and go to nationals.
Hey, are you from another school?
こら他校生かな勝手に入ちゃだめだよ
You're not allowed to be here.
Thank you for showing us around.
中見せてくれてありがとうございました
失礼します
Excuse us.
あの及川さんが県内で最強のセタなら
Um...
If Oikawa's the best setter in the prefecture,
それを超えるの俺なんで
then I'll be the one who surpasses him for that title.
失礼します
Excuse us.
Stamina, speed, agility, jumping, the will to fight...
スタミナスピド瞬発力バネ闘争心
Hinata Shouyou.
日向翔陽
Kageyama Tobio.
影山飛雄
Well, in reality,
まあ実際には
白鳥沢に勝てない青城に勝てない俺達だけど
it's true that we can't beat Seijou, who can't beat Shiratorizawa.
どちも倒せば関係ない
It doesn't matter if we can defeat them both.
分かてんじゃねぇか
Glad to see we're on the same page.
That's why we're going to Tokyo.
だから東京に行く
To get better, it's best if we play a lot against strong teams, right?
強くなるには強ぇやつとたくさんやんのが一番だろ
Ahem.
About that trip to Tokyo...
で例の東京遠征ですが
For now, we're planning to have it next month.
今のところ来月の予定です
遠征の場合親御さんの了承も必要だから
For trips like this, we'll need your permission from your guardians.
I'll pass out the paperwork later.
これも後で書類を配るね
学校からの承諾も基本的には大丈夫
As for consent from our school, it's basically all right.
However,
ただ来月になたら期末テストあるの分かるよね
as I'm sure you are aware,
you have final exams starting next month.
You are aware, right?
分かるよね
So, I think you know what I'm getting at,
で予想はついてるかもしれないけど
赤点の教科があた場合
but if you fail any subjects,
その補習が週末に行われるので
supplementary classes will be held that weekend.
Which means you won't be able to go to the away games.
遠征には行けないから
What happens if we skip our final exams?
期末テスト休んだらどうなるんだ
You retake them.
追試じゃない
What happens if you skip those?
じゃ追試も休んだら
追試の追試かな
Retake the retakes?
そうだ遠征から帰てくるまでテストを引き延ばしちゃえば
I know! We'll just take the tests after the away games!
仮病を使たら遠征も行けないでしょう
If you fake being sick, you can't go on the trip either.
You have my condolences.
ご愁傷様
Episode Two:
Direct Sunlight
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
次回ハイキュ直射日光
"Direct Sunlight."